So how do you even view the data for that?
You're gonna make use of two services, GL service
and Athena within the glue service.
We'll make use of Glue catalog
and we'll make use of Glue crawler
and we'll view it in Athena.
So what's a glue catalog?
Think of glue catalog as a repository that just
holds the metadata.
What is the metadata? It is not actual data,
it just holds the structure of the tables.
You'll come to know shortly what I mean by that. Okay.
What's a glue crawler?
Glue crawler will help you create the table. Okay?
And when you have a table, you can view the data in Athena.
Okay, now you'll see all of that shortly in fact.
So we'll go to AWS and search for glue.
We'll click on AWS glue here.
On the left hand side you have data catalog.
If you click on the databases, you'll see a few.
Here you'll create one database called As Mission,
D-E-H-H-O-F-N-Y-C-T-L-C.
And in this we'll have our table called us.
H-V-F-H-V-H-V-F-H-V. Now. Now what's the database?
Database here? Doesn't hold the data.
It is just a, a thing used
for logical organization of tables.
Okay, now what's a table? Table is something
which you can use.
Look at the data again, you'll come to that shortly.
Just gimme a few minutes. But I have this clear database is
it doesn't hold the data here,
it just holds the different tables.
Now here I have one table
and that table's location is shown as the
S3 bucket path where we have the data.
So this clearly indicates database doesn't hold the data.
Data is in S3 table also doesn't hold.
The data table is pointing to the S3 location.
And because this table is pointing to the S3 location,
if you drop this table, so choose this and click on delete
and see what happens to it.
In the S3 bucket, it still remains over there.
And because this behavior, this table is called
as an external table, it is, it's an external table.
It points to the data in S3 bucket.
This is an important concept.
External table interview caution.
So in the next few videos we'll actually create the database
and create the table.
The how is the table created.
As I said, the glue crawler will help us create the table.
If we scroll down here, call a crawler here, click on that
and you'll create one called as mission dh,
H-O-F-N-Y-C-T-L-C-H-V-F-H-V.
And I've shown how to create the crawler also.
And point this crawler
to the rest three location in the next few videos.
You can do that and run the crawler.
When you run the crawler, it's gonna create a table
for you automatically.
And that table is what you saw in the mission database.
Alright, another table is created. How do you view the data?
Now for that we will make Athena service.
We are back on the glue console.
When you click on the table data here,
It'll, and the query is already pre-written
for you here, just run it.
It'll show the data here. So now
we are able to view the data.
So this is what the requirement was.
The business analyst wanted to look at the data for them
to understand and define the requirements
for data engineer project.
But you are able to actually queries,
doesn't mean the data analysts can query it.
So what's the next step? The next step is gonna be for you
to contact the cloud engineering team.
You'll email them, you'll tell them, Hey, provide access
to this data set, to this database
and this table to the business data analysts.
And they'll take care of that is your initial work
or the next few videos.
We'll let you build and do all of this.
Alright, if you wanna learn more about S3, make sure
to watch the deep dive course for sure.
And I hope you are now excited
to actually work on this project.
And if you're really excited, type excited
in the comment below the video.
I'll read that. I wanna see how, if you're really excited,
talk to you soon.